CurriculumVitae Ednedson Da Silva

Ednedson Da Silva

IT Specialist / Warehouse

Phone: +353 87 291 0215 Email: ednedson@hotmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/edy-da-silva/

PROFILE

Analytical, versatile, self-motivated, business focused, driven by targets and delivering results.

SKILLS SUMMARY

IT Specialist (Application Support (Government projects for Road Safety Authority department: National Driving License System/NDLS, myroadsafety.ie portal, CVRT and NCT)

Analyst Engineer (Gas Analyst: Particles count, Helium and HO2/O2 traceability on ultra-high purity gases for Intel Ireland)

Warehouse Supervisor (Selections, Order Processing, Planning, Compliance and Regulation, Problem Solving)

EDUCATION

2018 - Fundamentals of Business Analysis

Udemy

2017 - Data Analytics

Cenit College

2016 - Financial Trading

Institute of Investing and Financial Trading

2012 - Warehouse Management

FETAC Level 7

2010 - Business Management

Institute of Technology Tallaght

CAREER HISTORY

– Present –

Upskilling

Occupation:

- Personal project on Stock Market (Analysis and automation with Python)
- Diploma in Full Stack Software Development (Code Institute)
- Project implementation in South America

CurriculumVitae Ednedson Da Silva

• 2018 - 2023 - SGS Ireland Ltd

Position: Data Analyst / Developer (Aggregating IT specialist)

Responsibilities:

- Provide insight and analysis through clear visual, written and verbal communication
- Audit, assure and monitor data quality
- Produce reports for Business Intelligence (Using: Python, Excel and Power BI)
- Create and maintain tables in SQL Server to store and reuse data
- Develop high level dashboards integrated with Databases for Government agencies and multinational companies
- Present application to customer and prospect
- Develop python scripts for data scraping (backend development)

Responsibilities: IT Support Specialist

- Provide technical support for applications
- Troubleshoot system and configure in appropriated order
- Follow-up on new releases to ensure effectiveness
- Image/reimage computers and add to corporation network
- Active directory and group permissions

Responsibilities: Analyst Engineer

- Complete particles count measurements on the process gas utility lines to ensure compliance after fabrication
- Complete Trace Oxygen and Trace Moisture measurements using high-end analytical equipment.
- Consult with Intel operations for completion of existing tools and preparation of analysis on new tools.
- · Perform quality walks and report on issues.

2013 – 2017 - Lidl Ireland GmbH

Position: Warehouse Supervisor

Responsibilities:

- Supervise the Warehouse Selection Department daily operations
- Allocate work to employees on daily bases and manage Rota, training staff, coach, appraisals, motivate and help staff achieving KPI
- Implement Health & Safety procedures, enforcing standards accordingly to company principles
- Driving Productivity: achieving high operational performance across warehouse sectors ensuring daily targets are met. Cost control measures, reducing overtime, monitoring absence, sick leaves
- Equipment and machinery availability and maintenance
- Liaise with other departments. Goods In, goods out, Supply Chain, Stores

CurriculumVitae Ednedson Da Silva

• 2011 - 2013 - DB Schenker (Intel Ireland)

Position: Logistics Exceptions Specialist

Responsibilities:

- Receiving Team. Goods inwards, paperwork and quantity checks
- Counting, verifying, system updating and reconcile against PO
- Exceptions: Oversupplied, undersupplied, incorrect paperwork, labelling, damages awaiting technical inspection, non- conformance
- Maintain high Health & Safety Stardards
- Maintain World First Class Warehousing operation
- TAPA Security Standard applied

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- Languages: English, Portuguese, Spanish (Basic)
- EU (Irish) and Mercosul citizen
- · Full driving license

REFERENCES

On request